Who has questions about the Freemasons?
[music]
In my hand, I have a Freemason Bible
from the 1950s and a whole bunch of
internal Freemason documents. Book of
the apprentice, book of the fellow
craft, book of the master mason, a
monitor, an officer's manual, the
constitution and bylaws, Masonic law and
customs, [music] and one entitled the
truth shall set you free. I'll be
honest, I don't know much about the
Freemasons except the stereotype [music]
that they have in modern society that
they're bad or evil. But I do know that
they originated in Europe in the 14th
century [music] and they were a special
class of masons who built all the
cathedrals and castles of the old world.
A lot of people think they're bad, but I
was reading their internal literature
and I'm not so sure. Let me show you
what I mean in the monitor and officer's
manual. This [music] one is from 1941.
They pray when they start. In the first
degree, they cover brotherly love,
relief, truth, temperance, fortitude,
prudence, and justice. [music]
Those all seem like pretty good things
to me. The fact that they have their own
Bible is very crazy because they have a
long-standing battle with the church,
specifically the Catholic church. In
1738, Pope Clement VII condemned them
openly. He didn't like them because of
their secret oaths, because they treated
all religions as the same and that they
mixed Protestants and Catholics. Then in
1751, Pope Benedict
reaffirmed the condemnation of the
Freemasons. Membership in the
organization has been banned by the
Catholic church since 1751 and then in
1983, Pope Benedict XVI reaffirmed its
forbidden status [music] and also said
that Freemasons may not receive Holy
Communion. The ban was reaffirmed 3
years ago in 2023. They're still
feuding. So why do the Freemasons have
their own Bible? Very, very curious to
me. Because a lot of their private and
confidential documents line up [music]
with church teachings that the exclusive
state control of public education is the
cause of great evil. I agree with that.
Do you agree with that? That every
system of education must be subject to
the rules of divine law. And it looks to
me like they're agreeing with the
Catholic church on a lot of things in
their literature. And they seem [music]
to take deep dives into the meat of the
subject. This is 160 questions and
answers intended to convey the average
Mason the [music] information every
Mason desires without taking the time to
research. They are very keen on
Solomon's Temple. Now, Solomon was the
reported [music] wisest man ever on
planet Earth and the building
construction dimensions and everything
of the temple are a key focus of their
studies. I think [music] these guys
deserve an honest look. Now, I have
their internal documents and I'm
wondering if I should release these
online or if I should keep them private
[music] and in confidential and respect
to the order. There's no copyright
information. They're obviously public
domain. Should I respect the order? So,
if you have any real first-hand
information on the Freemasons, please
let me know [music] cuz I am not sure
which way to go.